{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a 20 Vac series RC circuit, if 20 V is measured across the resistor and 40 V is measured across the capacitor, the applied voltage is:", "opta": "45 V", "optb": "50 V", "optc": "55 V", "optd": "60 V", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the equation below that represents the relationship between charge, capacitance, and voltage for a capacitor.", "opta": "Q = CV", "optb": "C = QV", "optc": "", "optd": "V = IR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is a capacitor fully charged?", "opta": "when the voltage across its plates is  of the voltage from ground to one of its plates", "optb": "when the current through the capacitor is the same as when the capacitor is discharged", "optc": "when the voltage across the plates is 0.707 of the input voltage", "optd": "when the current through the capacitor is directly proportional to the area of the plates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the reactive power in the given circuit?", "opta": "0 VAR", "optb": "691 VAR", "optc": "44.23 mVAR", "optd": "1.45 kVAR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the angle theta value for a 5.6 F capacitor and a 50-ohm resistor in series with a 1.1 kHz, 5 Vac source?", "opta": "27.3 degrees", "optb": "62.7 degrees", "optc": "\u201327.3 degrees", "optd": "\u201362.7 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a 4.7 F capacitor is connected to a 1 kHz source, what is its capacitive reactance?", "opta": "4.7 ohms", "optb": "29.5 ohms", "optc": "34 ohms", "optd": "213 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total capacitance?", "opta": "1 F", "optb": "12 F", "optc": "0.615 F", "optd": "8 F", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is this circuit?", "opta": "bandpass filter", "optb": "high-pass filter", "optc": "low-pass filter", "optd": "differentiator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After which time constant can a capacitor be considered to be fully charged?", "opta": "first", "optb": "third", "optc": "fifth", "optd": "seventh", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "You could increase the time constant of an RC circuit by", "opta": "adding a resistor in parallel with the circuit resistance", "optb": "adding a capacitor in parallel with the circuit capacitance", "optc": "increasing the amplitude of the input voltage", "optd": "exchanging the position of the resistor and capacitor in the circuit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor's rate of charge is considered:", "opta": "magnetic", "optb": "a current block", "optc": "linear", "optd": "exponential", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A resistor and an output capacitor form a series circuit with a square wave applied. The circuit is:", "opta": "an integrator", "optb": "a differentiator", "optc": "a multiplier", "optd": "a divider", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an open capacitor is checked with an ohmmeter, the needle will:", "opta": "stay on zero", "optb": "stay on infinity", "optc": "move from zero to infinity", "optd": "move from infinity to zero", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit's total current?", "opta": "4.57 mA", "optb": "9.327 mA", "optc": "11.570 mA", "optd": "13.830 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a capacitor is being charged, current flowing into the capacitor will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the phase shift between the voltage across the resistor and the voltage from the source?", "opta": "VR leads VS by 17\u00b0", "optb": "VR leads VS by 73\u00b0", "optc": "VR lags VS by 73\u00b0", "optd": "VR lags VS by 17\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor stores energy within a dielectric between the conducting plates in the form of:", "opta": "a magnetic field", "optb": "positive voltage", "optc": "negative voltage", "optd": "an electric field", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a capacitor is being charged, the voltage across its terminals will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "oppose the source", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 500 kHz signal source, what would be the value of a capacitor yielding a capacitive reactance of 1 k ?", "opta": "318 pF", "optb": "2 nF", "optc": "3.18 F", "optd": "2 F", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After a capacitor has charged for 1 tc, what percentage of current remains in the resistor?", "opta": "63.2", "optb": "36.8", "optc": "13.5", "optd": "5.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a current of 40 mA flows through a series circuit consisting of a 0.4 F capacitor and a resistor in series with a 4 kHz, 40 Vac source, what is the total circuit impedance?", "opta": "10", "optb": "100", "optc": "1 k", "optd": "1 M", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the capacitance of the circuit shown in the given circuit?", "opta": "0.066 F", "optb": "0.9 F", "optc": "65.97 pF", "optd": "900 pF", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an ac circuit, an output capacitor and a resistor are connected in series with an ac signal. What filter action will be the result?", "opta": "bandpass", "optb": "low-pass", "optc": "high-pass", "optd": "band-stop", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total opposition to current in a series RC circuit called?", "opta": "impedance", "optb": "inductance", "optc": "reactance", "optd": "resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true?", "opta": "The voltage to which a capacitor is charged can change instantaneously.", "optb": "The current in a capacitive circuit takes time to change.", "optc": "A fully charged capacitor appears as a short to dc current.", "optd": "An uncharged capacitor appears as a short to an instantaneous change in current.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a capacitive circuit, current flow is limited to", "opta": "charging periods", "optb": "discharging periods", "optc": "neither charging periods nor discharging periods", "optd": "both charging periods and discharging periods", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What circuit has the following frequency response?", "opta": "bandpass filter", "optb": "high-pass filter", "optc": "low-pass filter", "optd": "integrator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor is constructed of two parallel:", "opta": "conductors", "optb": "semiconductors", "optc": "inductors", "optd": "dielectrics", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following determines the capacitance of a capacitor?", "opta": "Plate area, dielectric strength, and plate separation", "optb": "Voltage rating, dielectric constant, and temperature coefficient", "optc": "Temperature coefficient, plate area, and plate separation", "optd": "Plate area, dielectric constant, and plate separation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most older types of paper capacitors have been replaced by which type of construction?", "opta": "electrolytic", "optb": "plastic film", "optc": "oxide casing", "optd": "waxed paper", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If C1, a 4.7 F capacitor, and C2, a 3.3 F capacitor are in series with 18 Vdc applied, what is the voltage across C1?", "opta": "3.3 V", "optb": "7.4 V", "optc": "6.6 V", "optd": "9.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of a series RC circuit that consists of a 0.22 F capacitor and a 200-ohm resistor connected to a 3 kHz source?", "opta": "214 ohms", "optb": "313 ohms", "optc": "414 ohms", "optd": "880 ohms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the reactance value for a capacitor installed in a dc circuit?", "opta": "zero", "optb": "moderate", "optc": "infinite", "optd": "cannot tell", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a purely capacitive circuit,", "opta": "current leads voltage by 90\u00b0", "optb": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0", "optc": "current lags voltage by 90\u00b0", "optd": "current and voltage have a phase relationship of 0\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take the capacitor in the given circuit to completely discharge if the switch was in position 2?", "opta": "22 ms", "optb": "69 ms", "optc": "345 ms", "optd": "420 ms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the capacitive reactance if I = 1 amp, V = 2 volts, C = 5 F, and frequency = 10 Hz?", "opta": "0.2", "optb": "0.5", "optc": "0.02", "optd": "0.003", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with a leaky capacitor?", "opta": "It is open.", "optb": "It is shorted.", "optc": "The dielectric resistance has increased.", "optd": "The dielectric resistance has decreased.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the value of a capacitor labeled 102?", "opta": "10,000 pF", "optb": "1000 pF", "optc": "1000 F", "optd": "10,000 F", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the dielectric constant of a capacitor is decreased, then its capacitance will:", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "be destroyed", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dielectric constant for ceramic?", "opta": "between 6 and 8000", "optb": "5.0", "optc": "between 5 and 1000", "optd": "3000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across a capacitor after being charged from a 100 V source for a period of one time constant?", "opta": "37.8 V", "optb": "38 V", "optc": "63 V", "optd": "101 V", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the dc charging/discharging time constant for the circuit?", "opta": "294 ps", "optb": "13.5 ms", "optc": "21.25 ms", "optd": "2.16 Gs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power stored from the source and then returned to the source is called:", "opta": "apparent power", "optb": "impedance power", "optc": "reactive power", "optd": "true power", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Capacitor value markings are usually:", "opta": "alphanumeric", "optb": "color dabs", "optc": "standard", "optd": "white print", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A source voltage across a capacitor will:", "opta": "lead the current by 90 degrees", "optb": "lead the current by 180 degrees", "optc": "lag the current by 90 degrees", "optd": "lag the current by 180 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long would it take the capacitor in the given circuit to completely charge if the switch was in position 1?", "opta": "22 ms", "optb": "69 ms", "optc": "345 ms", "optd": "440 ms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8 V power source is charging a capacitor. How many volts will be across the capacitor at the second time constant?", "opta": "1 volt", "optb": "3 volts", "optc": "5 volts", "optd": "7 volts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The material used between the plates of a capacitor is called its:", "opta": "insulation material", "optb": "dielectric material", "optc": "separation material", "optd": "plate-divider material", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a circuit consists of a capacitor and a resistor in series with a voltage source, and the voltage across the resistor is zero, then the capacitor is:", "opta": "charging", "optb": "discharging", "optc": "fully charged", "optd": "fully discharged", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which material has the highest dielectric strength?", "opta": "Air", "optb": "Paper", "optc": "Mica", "optd": "Oil", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit's impedance?", "opta": "1192", "optb": "843", "optc": "723", "optd": "511", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an ac circuit, a capacitor and an output resistor are connected in series with an ac signal. What filter action will be the result?", "opta": "bandpass", "optb": "low-pass", "optc": "high-pass", "optd": "band-stop", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of this circuit?", "opta": "5928", "optb": "2000", "optc": "1902", "optd": "1798", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Impedance Cannot be Directly Measured, We Need to find Xc first.\nSo,\nXc = 1/2\u03c0fC.\nXc = 1/( 2 x 3.14 x 5000 x 0.01 x 10-6 ).\nXc = 3184.7.\nZ = Sqrt( Xc2 + R2 ).\nZ = Sqrt( 3184.72 + 50002 ).\nZ = 5928 &ohm;."}, {"question": "What is the reactive power?", "opta": "6.8 mW", "optb": "9.8 mW", "optc": "12.8 mW", "optd": "15.8 mW", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A practical capacitor", "opta": "is a short to dc", "optb": "looks like a capacitor in parallel with a resistor", "optc": "is an open to ac", "optd": "stores energy in a magnetic field", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the reference vector for parallel RC circuits?", "opta": "R", "optb": "I", "optc": "C", "optd": "V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do variable capacitors use for dielectric?", "opta": "ceramic, electrolytic, mica, or paper", "optb": "air, ceramic, mica, or plastic", "optc": "ceramic, paper, plastic, or mica", "optd": "mica, ceramic, plastic, or electrolytic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a charged capacitor is disconnected from a circuit, it will:", "opta": "immediately discharge", "optb": "recharge", "optc": "remain charged", "optd": "leak the charge", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the total current for a 5 MHz, 1 Vac circuit that consists of a 27 pF capacitor and a 1 k resistor connected in parallel?", "opta": "459 A", "optb": "647 A", "optc": "1.31 mA", "optd": "1.85 mA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the value of a capacitor that can store two coulombs of charge when 500 volts is applied across its plates?", "opta": "4 F", "optb": "250 F", "optc": "4,000 F", "optd": "250 F", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The strength of an electric field at a given point is proportional to the potential difference on the plates and inversely proportional to the:", "opta": "plate separation", "optb": "negative plate only", "optc": "field strength", "optd": "charge difference", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is ac current related to ac voltage in a purely capacitive circuit?", "opta": "AC current is 0.707 of the ac voltage.", "optb": "AC current lags ac voltage.", "optc": "AC current is 0.637 of the ac voltage.", "optd": "AC current leads ac voltage.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the voltage across the capacitor?", "opta": "7.07 V", "optb": "1.11 V", "optc": "111 mV", "optd": "7.07 mV", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a given charge difference, electrostatic field strength varies according to:", "opta": "plate differential", "optb": "plate area", "optc": "plate distance", "optd": "dielectric quantity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor has 25 V across its plates and a stored charge of 1500 C. What is the capacitance value?", "opta": "60 pF", "optb": "60 F", "optc": "16.67 mF", "optd": "37.5 mF", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A capacitor and an output resistor form a series circuit with a square wave applied. The circuit is:", "opta": "an integrator", "optb": "a differentiator", "optc": "a multiplier", "optd": "a divider", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Capacitive reactance values connected in series offer", "opta": "an increase in total XC", "optb": "a decrease in total XC", "optc": "no change in total XC", "optd": "total opposition to voltage in the circuit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The quantity that represents an ideal capacitor dissipating 0 W of power is", "opta": "instantaneous power", "optb": "true power", "optc": "reactive power", "optd": "resistive power", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a capacitor is placed across a 20 V source, what will be the amount of charge after 5 tc?", "opta": "5.0 V", "optb": "12.8 V", "optc": "13.5 V", "optd": "20 V", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the impedance of an ac RC parallel circuit if the resistance is 12 ohms and the capacitive reactance equals 5 ohms?", "opta": "0.2 ohms", "optb": "3.5 ohms", "optc": "4.6 ohms", "optd": "13 ohms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What will a 1 F capacitor store?", "opta": "one coulomb of charge", "optb": "6.24 x 1012 electrons", "optc": "one volt", "optd": "one A of current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an RC circuit, true power (PR) equals:", "opta": "", "optb": "VS \u00d7 I", "optc": "I2R", "optd": "VT \u00d7 RT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power factor if the apparent power of a circuit is 5 W, while the true power is 4 W?", "opta": "0.0 W", "optb": "0.8 W", "optc": "1.0 W", "optd": "1.25 W", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the reactive power of a circuit is 50 mW while the apparent power is 64 mW, then what is the true power of the circuit?", "opta": "14 mW", "optb": "36 mW", "optc": "40 mW", "optd": "114 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}